hello this is a New Year's Eve 2023
video that's giving a bit of a look
towards how we'll be doing projects and
participation at the Active inference
Institute in 2024 so I'm on the homepage
of the onboarding document and I'm going
to head over to
projects as figure one from our recent
2023 paper shows projects are at the
heart of participating in The Institute
and in the acadm ecosystem projects
include the CORE Institute projects that
are commons like or infrastructural such
as the active inference ontology Journal
Productions and live streams and so on
and also there are so many projects
learning and application that people are
working on in the active inference
ecosystem and some that engage with or
are hosted at The Institute so drawing
on work in Quantum active inference
which the second half of this video is
going to explore a little bit of we're
planning to structure project proposal
and Reporting at The Institute in 2024
according to these two stages and each
stage with a form and the two stages are
preparation and measurement for
preparing a project it's like proposing
a project that could be informing The
Institute about a project that is
already going to be happening and
doesn't require support all the way on
up through requested support in the form
of calendar events Discord channels
funding different kinds of support and
hosting at The Institute and then active
projects will be found in the activities
tab so that there can be this updated
list of what is really living and
ongoing at The Institute how can one get
involved what is that project looking to
do and then what else has that project
already done will be reflected by the
always open measurement form and this
could be a project that was proposed
initially to The Institute and carried
out intern internally or it could just
be a research paper that somebody found
or created and can be a opportunity for
future preparation engagement or not so
here from this projects page you can
click into the project preparation form
unfold and see the questions if you want
to copy them out and then directly
complete the form for project
preparation here or click the form link
and similarly for project meas
you can unfold what questions are on the
form click the form link or you can fill
it out directly on the coded
document that's a little bit of the how
a little bit of the low road and we hope
to continue to fine-tune and develop on
that in the second part of this video I
want to look a little bit to this part
that was mentioned about the quantum
active inference so clicking that link
will take you to the syllabus for the
course physics as information processing
which Chris Fields taught with the
assistance of Andre in
2023 and we recently published just
today the transcript from this course
and so I'm going to pull up in the
transcript where preparation measurement
was mentioned so here's the quantum
informatic Alice Through Time preparing
and
measuring a Quantum reference frame
everything not explicitly forbidden is
mandatory all the paths and then what's
really taken is measured so this is the
proposal stage here's how it could go
here's our situation and context and
here's the kind of distributional or
procedural approach that we're taking
and then measurement empirically what
happened and so
here basically what fainman realized was
that in any physical process The
Observer Alice prepares some state that
she's interested in she prepares some
input to an experiment
then she lets something
happen and then she sees what the result
of the experiment is and the canonical
experiment in physics is scattering you
know fire two protons at each other and
they intersect someplace and stuff comes
out and you measure the stuff that comes
out so I'm sure there's many other areas
where we can search for prepare and
measure and find a lot of technical
depth and a lot of discussion from this
very interesting course but even from
that short select
there's so many ways to think about
preparation and measurement so it's
really exciting that people on their own
timelines according to their own time
scales and preferences can propose
things to The Institute whether we could
provide you the support that is going to
make the project continue or not or
whether we can help something get off
the ground or just learn about what
you're proposing we will try with this
new system to stay on top of things stay
responsive and we look forward to
versioning all of this with everyone so
email us at blanket active inference
Institute if you have any other thoughts
or questions otherwise see you in 24
peace